Rohit Kumar

Address: 8, Selsey Road, Crawley – RH11 9HR Telephone (mobile): 07938 027 761

Email: rohitk23@gmail.com

Professional profile

An experienced Business Operations and Administration professional with substantial experience of driving organisational strategy and performance within the IT industry with a proven track record in account management, business development and also enhancing customer service standards. Demonstrable experience leading a diverse team to create, implement and deliver objectives of the organisation covering digital strategy and the implementation of e-commerce, marketing automation and Content Management Systems (CMS). Able to manage the organisational reputation, overseeing customer relationships and contractors while managing the overall financial performance. Possesses a proven track record managing large scale operations including ensuring efficient use of resources, maintenance and improvement in customer service standards, and collaborative working internally and externally. Highly confident at managing business development teams and coordinating numerous assets and processes to deliver company objectives. A driven and professional individual with exceptional organisational and communication skills, is able to adapt to new situations, coach and develop staff, and willing to assume additional responsibility.

Key Skills

- Business Development
- Operations Management
- Office Management
- Marketing and Campaign Management
- Managing Budgets and Forecasting

- Account Management
- Relationship Management
- RFP, RFQ, Tender Response
- Invoicing, Accounting, Credit control, Payroll
- Recruitment

Career Summary

Apr 19 - Till date

EMPOVER I-TECH

Empover is a web and mobile development company that specializes in custom application development, mobile computing, enterprise application integrations and digital analytics.

Business Operations Manager

Responsibilities:

- · Business plans, budgeting and forecasting
- Bank reconciliations, invoicing and accounts payable
- Producing website and marketing content, email and social media campaigns
- Account management, requirements gathering and delivery strategy

Feb 19 – Apr 19 MIND TOOLS

Mind Tools is one of the world's most popular digital, on-demand career and management learning solutions, helping more than 24 million people each year. Many top global organizations also use Mind Tools Corporate to increase productivity, improve management and leadership skills, and support organizational development initiatives. Mind Tools work with companies around the world – from start-ups to multinational corporations and support our clients by providing a consumer-style, on-demand learning environment.

Finance Accountant

Responsibilities:

- Bank reconciliations of multiple Pound Sterling, US Dollar, AU Dollar and Euro currency accounts.
- Chase, PayPal and WorldPay account reconciliations
- Generating Vindicia reports
- Purchase ledger and Sales Ledger management
- Invoice generation, supplier payment runs on multiple currencies, employee expenses processing and credit cards expense management
- Finance mailbox management
- Accounting software QuickBooks Online
- Miscellaneous tasks Administration of Adobe account user licenses and Getty images account, petty cash management and general payments.

Jun 2018 – Feb 2019 GATE GOURMET

Gate Gourmet is the world's largest independent airline catering, hospitality and logistics company. It is the core business behind gategroup, whose eleven associated brands offer customers a comprehensive scope of products and services for virtually any on-board need. Gate Gourmet provides more than 200 million meals a year to 270-plus customers at some 120 airport locations around the globe. Some of its clients are British Airways, Virgin Atlantic, Air Canada, Air Transat, American Airlines, United Airlines, Qantas, Air China, Air France, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Swiss International Air Lines, and EasyJet.

AP / Operations Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Processing all Gatwick branch invoices, query resolutions, credit and payments reconciliations and supplier account consolidations.
- On-board sales checkouts and returns process management for Norwegian Airlines
- Short and Long haul catering forecast and production reports for Norwegian Airlines
- Generating LGW financial turnover and labour reports
- Generating consumption reports
- Used Gate Gourmet's SACS ERP platform and MS Excel for all activities listed above.

May 2011 – Dec 2017 TA DIGITAL

https://www.tadigital.com/

TA Digital (TechAspect) is a digital transformation company with expertise in Content Management Systems (CMS), e-commerce, and Marketing Automation solutions. The Company covers a range of platforms and technologies such as WCMS systems including Adobe AEM, Sitecore, TeamSite, Drupal and WordPress.

Business Operations Manager - UK

Key Achievements:

• Generated sales on average of £500k to £700k per annum since 2012 and ensured business development activity supported continued growth.

Responsibilities:

- Developing the business plan and budgets for the forthcoming year based on expected sales activities and identifying resource requirements to ensure all work is successfully delivered to a high standard
- Responsible for managing key client accounts, understanding their requirements and challenges, and devising a technology strategy to fully service their operations and achieve their objectives
- Lead qualification, outbound marketing by email and social media campaigns, inbound lead follow-ups.
- Preparing and presenting detailed presentations including the business solutions, the approach, the costs involved and projections of increased financial performance
- Identifying opportunities to cross and up sell additional products and services that will compliment the client's existing investment strategy
- Working closely with the implementation and delivery teams to understand the progress and assisting them in any issues they may encounter
- Working closely with Bid Managers on both public and private sector RFP, RFQ and Tender responses
- Maintaining client relationships by establishing strong working and trusting relationships through ensuring their requirements are addressed and performance expectations are exceeded accordingly
- Managed an offshore team of inside sales resources, delegated tasks and ensured various KPIs were met.
- Payroll management, credit control, invoicing and accounting process management.
- Reported directly to CEO in US.
- Used CRM softwares; HubSpot and MS Dynamics.

Jul 2008 – Apr 2011 TECHASPECT (India) National Sales Manager

Key Achievements:

- Fully developed an innovative marketing strategy, business development processes and devising a structured and attractive commission structure for the company
- Devised a coherent recruitment strategy and plan for all offshore segments ensuring the most suitable technical staff were recruited

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing the sales teams, including setting targets, enhancing sales performance, and achieving profit margins through oversight of new business development activity
- Overseeing new business development activity and approving the sales strategy to maintain profit margins while optimising existing relationships and opportunities

- Planning sales activity for the forthcoming period, reviewing sales performance and adapting sales approach to successfully convert leads to sales
- Providing clients with an all-round service including promoting products and services that may meet their requirements and explaining the finer details to establish a long lasting relationship
- Coaching and developing staff to enhance their sales performance, setting objectives, and appraising performance regularly in line with company policies and procedures

May 2006 – May 2008 PROFREC LIMITED (UK) Senior Resourcer and Account Manager

Key Achievements:

- Undertaking end to end recruitment for Business and IT based positions for major clients including investment banks, Lloyds underwriting agencies and market data companies
- Successfully recruited for key clients covering various technical roles including Middleware Consultants/Developers, Programmer Analysts, Database Developers, Administrators and Support Staff, ERP Professionals, Testers, Project/Programme Managers and Business Analysts

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing key client accounts covering all technical and functional aspects of the recruitment service key clients including Lloyds underwriting agencies and market-data companies
- Liaising with clients to fully understand their requirements and priorities for each role as well as fully understanding their market to ensure candidates are fully briefed prior to being considered for the role
- Managing client and candidate relationships and ensuring a long standing relationship is established as part of building a large and strong portfolio of candidates
- Negotiating contract rates with clients and managing the negotiation between clients and candidates to ensure both parties are satisfied with the agreed salary package
- Undertaking comprehensive search activities for clients including collating CVs from key CV data-bases including Jobsite, Monster, Jobserve and Totaljobs
- Preparing advertisements and marketing of roles in appropriate recruitment channels including jobsites and recruitment portals to attract applicants
- Matching candidates and clients based on their capabilities including considering personality and organisational fit based on the client's priorities

Jun 2005 - May 2006 PMR TECHNOLOGIES (UK) - Resourcer and Account Manager

Dec 2003 - Oct 2004 RAMADIA OUTSOURCING SERVICES PVT LIMITED (India) - Senior Client Services

Executive

Jan 2000 - Sep 2002 ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY GROUP INC (USA) - Business Development Manager

1998 – 1999 WAYNE STATE UNIVERSITY (USA) - Program Coordinator

Education and Qualifications

B.E: Bachelors of Engineering (Industrial Engineering), Bangalore Institute of Technology,

(1997)

Additional Information

Nationality: UK, British passport
Licence: Full UK Driving License
Languages: English, Hindi, Tamil

Interests: Playing cricket, Reading, Socializing

References are available on request